#### Contact

347-684-2345 (Mobile) timhiggins7@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/timothyhiggins-ms-rn-ccrn-k-cencpen-38008356 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing

Healthcare

Healthcare Management

### Certifications

Certification in Emergency Nursing (CEN)

Certified Pediatric Emergency Nurse (CPEN)

Certification in Critical Care Nursing

– Adult Knowledge (CCRN-K)

# Timothy Higgins, MS, RN, CCRN-K, CEN, CPEN

Nurse Leader | Educator Greater New York City Area

## Summary

I am an extremely motivated, goal driven, nurse leader and educator with over 11 years of experience in healthcare. As a dedicated professional, I have built a solid background in many key areas impacting the delivery of healthcare services. Specifically, I have obtained solid results in improving clinical outcomes and enhancing the patient experience, while increasing performance in the acute care setting. I have successfully managed large, interdisciplinary teams, caring for diverse patient populations within large academic regional trauma centers. In addition to my work accomplishments, I have enjoyed many academic achievements such as maintaining a 4.0 GPA during my graduate studies, and obtaining several national certifications in nursing.

I am extremely grateful to have gained tremendous experience in my training as a staff nurse in the emergency department of a level 1 trauma center in the heart of New York City. Further developing and growing professionally as I excelled in roles within nursing management, education, and hospital administration. In addition to my employment experience, I have remained extremely active within professional organizations, seeking opportunities to draw upon my background in government and politics to advocate for my colleagues and patients.

## Experience

The Execu|Search Group
Registered Nurse - COVID Testing Site
March 2020 - Present (3 months)
New York City Metropolitan Area

NYC Health + Hospitals

Assistant Director of Nursing, Department of Nursing, Adult & Pediatric Emergency Services

2020 - 2020 (less than a year)

Bronx, New York

Jamaica Hospital
Education Specialist
2019 - 2020 (1 year)
New York City Metropolitan Area

Excelsior College Adjunct Professor-Clinical Examiner 2019 - 2020 (1 year) New York City Metropolitan Area

Northwell Health

7 years

Administrator, Hospital Operations
December 2014 - October 2018 (3 years 11 months)

Nurse Educator, Emergency Department August 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 5 months)

Assistant Nurse Manager, Patient Care Services-Emergency Department 2013 - July 2013 (less than a year)

RN, Emergency Services 2011 - 2013 (2 years)

LaGuardia Community College Adjunct Professor January 2013 - June 2015 (2 years 6 months)

NYC Health + Hospitals Staff Nurse, Adult Emergency Services 2008 - 2011 (3 years)

The Pond at Bryant Park General Manager 2006 - 2009 (3 years) Geto & de Milly, Inc.
Public Affairs Assistant
2007 - 2007 (less than a year)
New York, NY

NYS Assemblymember Michael Cohen Director of Legislative & Community Affairs 2003 - 2005 (2 years)

**US Congress** 

3 years

Director of Military & Veterans Affairs 2001 - 2002 (1 year)

Joseph Crowley

District Representative January 1999 - December 2000 (2 years) Thomas J. Manton

New York City Council Legislative Intern September 1998 - January 1999 (5 months)

## Education

Capella University

Doctor of Nursing Practice (DNP), Nursing (2019 - 2021)

**Excelsior College** 

Master of Science (M.S.), Nursing Leadership & Healthcare Adminsitration  $\cdot$  (2013)

Laguardia Community College

Associate of Applied Science, Nursing · (2008)

John Jay College (CUNY)
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Political Science and Government · (2003)

Archbishop Molloy High School (1996)